A Guide to the Ruth Ford Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #10124-a
Ruth Ford Collection 1947-1960
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
10124-a
20 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the Library's microfilms of the William Faulkner manuscripts in its custody; the microfilm may be consulted by any interested party, and it will be lent through the interlibrary loan system. Materials are constantly added. Long-term loans may be arranged. Use of the microfilm will be restricted to the premises of the borrowing library. No loans will be made to individuals. Researchers should enquire of the Manuscripts Division concerning availability of microfilm of manuscripts that are pertinent to their work. Most of the literary manuscripts in our collections written by Faulkner, both holograph and typescript, have also been published in facsimile in William Faulkner Manuscripts, 25 vols (New York: Garland, 1986-87).
By the terms of the agreement by which the William Faulkner Foundation transferred the original manuscripts to the University, access to the original manuscripts is restricted (to ensure the survival of the physically-delicate originals) to doctoral candidates at the dissertation stage of their programs, and to certain mature scholars and critics. But even these researchers must demonstrate need to see the originals that goes beyond the requirements of most routine research. A doctoral candidate at the dissertation stage, or other qualified researcher who believes that his or her work requires access to the originals must correspond with the Curator of Manuscripts prior to arrival at the Library to obtain permission for access.
No microfilm, electrostatic, or other types of copies may be made of materials written by William Faulkner that are in our William Faulkner Collections. Other materials in the collections may be copied subject to the normal rules of the Library established under the conditions of the Copyright Act. All copying is performed by the Printing Services Department of the University.
Acquisition Information
Gift
Scope and Content
The first box of this collection contains William Faulkner material and is located in the vault.
RUTH FORD COLLECTION
- >MANUSCRIPTS
  - " The Wishing Tree " by William Faulkner inscribed to Shelley "Ford" [Scott], daughter of Ruth Ford, Christmas 1948; TLS(carbon) in blue slipcase w/env in which it was mailed 43 p.
  - Requiem for a Nun: complete script for the play with corrections and additions by William Faulkner and others, [1951]; TMs 119 p.
  - Requiem for a Nun: partial script (some carbons) for the play with corrections and additions by William Faulkner and others, [1951]; TMs 93 p. (90r, 3v) on 90 l.
  - Requiem for a Nun: partial script for the play with corrections and additions by William Faulkner and others, [1951]; TMs Act I only, 26 p.
  - Requiem for a Nun: partial script (some carbons) for the play with corrections and additions by William Faulkner and others, [1951]; TMs mostly Act I, 37 p. (36r, 1v) on 36 l.
  - Requiem for a Nun: random pages of the play with additions and corrections by William Faulkner and others, [1951]; TMs 3 p.
  - Requiem for a Nun: partial script (some carbons) for the play with corrections and additions by William Faulkner and others, [1951]; TMs 26 p.
  - Requiem for a Nun: partial script for the play with corrections and additions by William Faulkner and others, [1951]; TMs 20 p.
  - Requiem for a Nun: random pages of a script for the play with corrections and additions by William Faulkner and others, [1951]; TMs 87 p.
  - fragments/envelope/printed page Typed and holograph additions to the script for Requiem for a Nun; envelope addresseed in Faulkner's hand to Ruth Ford; statement about the play and RF which Faulkner wrote for the novel., 1947 Apr 3, n. d.; TMs
- CORRESPONDENCE
  - William Faulkner to Ruth Ford, 1950 Jan 31; telegram
  - Bill [Faulkner] to Ruth [Ford], [1951]; TLS 1 p.
  - Bill to Ruth, 1957 Oct 1; TLS w/env 1 p.
  - Saxe [Cummins] to Ruth [Ford], 1958 Mar 14; TLS 1 p.
    w/ANS, Bill to Ruth
  - Bill to Ruth, 1959 Jan 2; TLS w/env 1 p.
  - Estelle [Faulkner] and Bill to Ruth, 1959 Mar 5; telegram
- MISCELLANEOUS
  - Radio broadcast publicity program for Broadway opening of William Faulkner's play Requiem for a Nun, 1959 Feb 6
    Ruth Ford and Zachary Scott analyze the play and discuss aspects of its creation and production
  - Bill to Ruth and Zachary [Scott], [1960 Jan 21]; ALS w/env 1 p.
  - Bill to Ruth, Jun 20; ALS w/env 1 p.
  - Bill to Ruth, Thursday; ALS 1 p.